Brooke Ly

I'm a 4th year Computer Science student with a passion for creating and developing content. I'd like to expand and utilize my experience as a student as well as a tech mentor helping students code in a role as a software developer or engineer.

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine — Computer Science

OCT 2014 - Present

Expected Graduation Date: December 2018

EXPERIENCE

Google igniteCS, Irvine, CA — Coding Mentor

April 2017 - May 2017

• Outreach workshop designed by Google. Taught high school students how to code using Scratch, Makey Makey boards, and Processing.

Spoon University, — *Marketing Director/Chapter Co-founder*

FEB 2016 - MARCH 2017

- Planned themed community events that integrate 5 colleges communities.
- Fostered partnerships with local businesses and/or campus organizations to increase retention rates to the local business and the club itself.
- Developed promotional campaigns to advertise community events.
- Created quarterly marketing plans to ensure the club grows.

LinkedIn UI Externship, Sunnyvale, CA

MARCH 2016

Job shadowed engineers and designers of the Ads and Mobile Team. Learned software development processes and observed what a day in the life of an engineer and designer entails.

AMC Glass Co., San Jose, CA — Office Assistant

IUNE 2012 - IUNE 2015

- Distributed marketing and communication materials to local community
- Entered customer information and custom orders into system database
- Assisted customers with pick-up orders and provided quotes for custom orders.

PROJECTS

BeautyBae — Course Project for CS 122b (Java, SQL, HTML)

Designed and developed BeautyBae, an ecommerce website for our CS 122b project class. With my group, we maintained the website with data management techniques and web application development tools.

Graphs and Dijkstra's Algorithm — Course Program for ICS 46

Implemented HashGraph with HashMap and HashSet. Used HashGraph to implement an extended version of Dijkstra's shortest path algorithm.

3900 Parkview Ln, Apt 32B Irvine, CA 92612

(408) 375-4807

lybrooke96@gmail.com LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/2dP6Equ

Github: http://bit.ly/2pewagj

AWARDS + ORGANIZATIONS

2017 ICS/BRAID Scholarship University California, Irvine was able to attend the Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing.

Alpha Phi Omega (Member) is a co-educational national service fraternity. Participated in community and nation based services such as the IDRF walk that funds research for type 1 diabetes.

Women in Computer Science (Mentor) A social and professional organization established to help and encourage women to pursue a college degree and a successful career in the computer science field.

LANGUAGES

C/C++, Python, Java, Intermediate Web Programming (HTML, CSS)

SKILLS

Google Drive, Database Management, Marketing